CURRICULUM VITAE

I have experience in the hospitality industry, however, my true passion has always been in programming and development, and I have strong attention to detail and inclination for problem-solving. To build upon this interest, I have graduated from a Coding Traineeship as a full stack developer. Upon graduation, I have worked as a freelance software developer creating and updating web applications and websites for clients. I have real-world experience developing websites and applications, excellent customer service, communication, teamwork and organisation skills and a strong work ethic. I am looking forward to establishing a career in the development field where I can prove myself as an asset.

PERSONAL DETAILS

NAME: Michael Pontes Rushton

RESIDES: Algarve, Portugal

TRANSPORT: Public transport

LANGUAGES: English

RIGHT TO WORK: UK Citizen and Portuguese Citizen

CONTACT DETAILS: (M) (UK) +44 7517 099844 (PTG) +351 910 329 166

(E) mrush94ton@gmail.co.uk (W) https://mikejprushton.com/ (GH) https://github.com/Nothsurm/

(LinkedIn) https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-rushton-65316b280/

CODING TRAINEESHIP IT Career Switch Ltd

Coding Traineeship - Full stack developer

1-year program

During the traineeship I had to demonstrate a very competent level of the following programming languages and technical skills

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

- PHP, SQL, React, jQuery
- Python, Node.js, Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS, Command line Git, Github
- Remote API access

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES:

Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB

FREELANCE EXPERIENCE:

Since December 2023 I have been freelancing on Upwork.com. More details of my freelance work can be found on my Upwork profile below:

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~0187be7100cd5c9eef

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE:

Below are the projects I have completed, additional information on these projects can be found in my portfolio: https://mikejprushton.com/

Portfolio Project #1: "Rush-Eats"

A full-stack MERN food-ordering platform designed with typescript. This application is fully responsive in all screen sizes. Utilises TanStack query for handling api requests and Zod for form-handling. Payment is secure using Stripe in development mode. Backend uses Node.js and Express.js to connect to a MongoDB database.

Portfolio Project #2: "Metropolis"

A full-stack e-commerce application. Users may filter and purchase products using PayPal Developer. Jsonwebtokens are utilised for login security. Redux is used for maintenance and storage of data. The app is fully responsive and declares a modern UI design.

Portfolio Project #3: "Rushton Properties"

A full-stack MERN application that uses React in the front-end and Express.js and Node.js in the back-end to connect to a database in MongoDB. This fully responsive application uses Firebase for google authentication. The application is completely error-free.

Additional projects and client websites I maintain can be found on my Upwork profile: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~0187be7100cd5c9eef

CAREER HISTORY:

2023-2024(present) POSITION HELD:

Upwork.com

Freelance Software Developer

- Created and maintain clients websites and applications
- Communicate directly with potential clients about their software related problems
- Upsell my own skillset to potential clients

2021 – 2023 POSITION HELD:

Agency Labourer

- Worked on numerous construction sites carrying various hard manual labour activities
- Managed and handled deliveries
- Maintained tools and equipment of the tradesmen on site
- Performed set-up and clean-up tasks at site
- Directed traffic near site

2018 – 2021 POSITION HELD:

Dukes92 Bartender

- Developed important time-management skills in one of busiest bars in the city
- Liaised with Bar Manager on inventory and bar supplies
- Knowledge of traditional cocktails
- Processed payments
- Good customer service

2019 – 2020 Bill's POSITION HELD: Bartender

- Developed professionalism and good customer service skills
- Maintained cleanliness of bar by daily upkeep
- Developed situational awareness
- Developed barista skills
- Essential to have good communication with colleagues to ensure smooth service

2016 – 2018 POSITION HELD:

Scene Indian Street Kitchen Bar Manager

- Started off as a bar back and over a few months worked up to a bar manager in charge of a six-person bar team
- Responsible for bar supply and deliveries
- Maintained good quality bar standard and service
- Taught bar standards to new employees

VOLUNTEERING:

Sep 2012 – Jan 2017 POSITION HELD:

Pencalenick School Learning Mentor

 Led the Pastoral Team, who provided support to children with significant behavioural or learning difficulties

EDUCATION:

2013 – 2016 Bolton University

Undergraduate Sports and Exercise Science

2011 – 2013 Bolton Sixth Form College

BTEC Sports Science

2005 – 2010 St. Monica's RC High School

Six GCSEs (Grade: $A^* - C$)